Guide to the College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences Records
University of Houston Libraries
College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences Records
1940-2009
2009-008
University of Houston. College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences
9.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
These records contain 9 boxes relating to the various departments that make up the College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences at the University of Houston. A significant portion of this material was given to the archives from the university Print Plant.
Historical Note:
The College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences is a fairly new college in its current state, but it has a long tradition at the university. In the early days of the university, the components of CLASS were part of the College of Arts and Sciences. In the early 1970s, this college was divided into the College of Humanities, Fine Arts, and Communication (HFAC), the College of Social Sciences (SOS), and the College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics (NSM). In 2000, SOS and HFAC were brought together to form CLASS. Its departments and schools occupy buildings ranging from the oldest building on campus, Roy G. Cullen Hall, to among the newest, like the Moores School of Music building. CLASS faculty teach nearly 10,000 students every semester, at both undergraduate and graduate levels. Some current CLASS departments have been offering baccalaureate degrees since UH became a four-year institution in the 1930s. The first doctoral degrees were conferred in departments like History and Political Science in the mid 1970s. The Sarah Campbell Blaffer Gallery, the university’s art museum that is housed in CLASS, was dedicated in 1973 and the Cynthia Woods Mitchell Center for the Arts, was completed in late 2005.
CLASS’s 15 departments and schools all offer undergraduate and master’s degrees, and seven offer doctoral degrees. The College also has seven programs offering undergraduate minors. Cultural centers, like the Sarah Campbell Blaffer Gallery and the Cynthia Woods Mitchell Center for the Arts also make their home in CLASS.
With disciplines ranging from Art to Theatre, Anthropology to Sociology, and African American Studies to Women’s Studies, the College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences is the largest and most diverse of the twelve colleges at the University of Houston.
Source:
About the college; A Brief History of CLASS, available from www.class.uh.edu. 12 August 2009
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston; University of Houston. College of Arts and Sciences; University of Houston. College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
These records contain 9 boxes relating to the various departments that make up the College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences at the University of Houston. A significant portion of this material was given to the archives from the university Print Plant. Material includes correspondence, course information, event programs and flyers, invitations, promotional material, published material, newsletters, stationary, Self-Study reports, and Five-Year plans. The collection is arranged alphabetically by department title. Material ranges in date from the 1930s to 2009.
Detailed List of Contents
- Files by Department
  - African Studies (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - African American Studies (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agriculture, 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Humanities (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anthropology, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Anthropology, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Art, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Art - Flyer/Stationery, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arté Publico, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arté Publico - envelopes, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arté Publico - Luncheon with Lantigua, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Arté Publico - Trade Catalog, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arté Publico, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Arts Calendar, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Arts Calendar, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Arts Calendar, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Arts Calendar, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Arts Calendar, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Asian American Studies (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Blaffer, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Blaffer, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Blaffer, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Blaffer, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Blaffer, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Blaffer, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Blaffer, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Blaffer, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Blaffer, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Blaffer, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Blaffer, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Blaffer, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Blaffer, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Blaffer, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Blaffer, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Blaffer, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Blaffer, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Blaffer, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Blaffer, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Blaffer, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 39-40)
  - Center for Immigration Research (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Center for Integrative Studies (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Center for Mexican American Studies, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Center for Mexican American Studies, 1944-1978 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Center for Mexican American Studies, 1982-1999 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Center for Mexican American Studies, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Center for Mexican American Studies - Academic Achievers Program (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Center for Public History (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Center for Public Policy (Box 2, Folder 1a)
  - College of Humanities, Fine Arts, and Communication - Bylaws (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - C.L.A.S.S. - Commencement & Convocation (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - C.L.A.S.S. - Correspondence - “division of CLASS”, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - C.L.A.S.S. - General (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - C.L.A.S.S. - Newsletters (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - C.L.A.S.S. - Stationery (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences - Envelopes (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences - Envelopes (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Communications, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Communications, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Communications, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Communications, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Communications, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Communications, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Communications, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - C.R.E.A.T.E. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cynthia Woods Mitchell Center for the Arts, 2000s (Box 2, Folder 16a)
  - Department of Modern & Classical Languages, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Division of Foreign Languages, 1950s- 1960s (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Economics, 1962-1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Economics, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - English, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - English, 1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - English, 1962-1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - English, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - English, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - English, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - English, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - English, 1990-2000s (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - French, 1946-1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - German, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - German, 1963-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Russian, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Spanish, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Spanish, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Spanish, 1974-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Geography, 1970's (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hispanic Studies, 2000's (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - History, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - History, 1956-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - History, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - History, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - History, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - History, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - History, 1991-1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - History, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - History, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Home Economics, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Home Economics, 1940s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Home Economics, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Home Economics, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Home Economics, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - India Studies Program (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Institute for Urban Studies (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Music - Ives Fund (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Music - Study Club “The Lyre”, 1/1934 thru 2/1935 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Music - Study Club “The Lyre”, 2/1935 thru 5/1935 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Music - Study Club “The Lyre”, 2/1935 thru 12/1935 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Music - Study Club “The Lyre”, 12/1935 thru 4/1936 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Music - Study Club The Lyre”, 4/1936 thru 9/1936 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Music - “The Lyre”, 11/1951 thru 11/1952 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Music, undated (Box 3, Folder 31-33)
  - Music, 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Music, 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Music, 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Music, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Music, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Music, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Music, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Music, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Music, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Music, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Music, January- May, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Music, June-December 1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Music, January-April 1979 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Music, May-December 1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Music, January-May, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Music, June-December, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Music, January-April, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Music, May-December, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Music, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Music, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Music, January-April, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Music, May-December, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Music, January-April, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Music, May-December, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Music, January-April, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Music, May-December, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Music, January-April, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Music, May-December, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Music, January-May,1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Music, June-December, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Music, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Music, January-May, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Music, June-December, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Music, January-May, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Music, June-December, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Music, January-May1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Music, June-December, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Music, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Music, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Music, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Music, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Music, January-June, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Music, July-December, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Music, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Music, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Music, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Music, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Music, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Music, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Music, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Music, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Music - Applications, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Music - Concert Programs, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Music - Correspondence, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Music - School Information, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Music - Stationery, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Music - Abiola Proposal Meeting, April 11, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Nursing (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Philosophy (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Philisophy, Religion (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Photography 344 - Donald C. Uhrbrock (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Political Sciences, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Political Sciences, 1947-1990s (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Political Sciences, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Psychology, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Psychology, 1952-1957 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Psychology, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Psychology, 1960-1965 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Psychology, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Texas Monthly - Most Valuable Players, September, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Psychology, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Psychology, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Psychology, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Psychology, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Psychology, 1980-1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Psychology, 1990-2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Psychology, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Psychology Research and Service Center (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Recovering U.S. Hispanic Literacy Heritage (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Religious Studies (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - ROTC, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - ROTC, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - ROTC, 1950-1959 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - ROTC, 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - ROTC, 1970-1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - ROTC, 1976-1979 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - ROTC, 1980-1988 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - ROTC, 2006-2014 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Social Science Alumni Association (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Social Science Quarterly Stationery (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Sociology (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
  - Theatre & Dance - envelopes, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 23-27)
  - Theatre & Dance - event flyers, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Theatre & Dance - letterhead, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Theatre & Dance, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Theatre & Dance - School Information (flyers), 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Theatre / Drama, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1939-1949 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1950-1955 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1956-1959 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1960-1964 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1972-1975 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1993-1996 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Theatre / Drama, 1997-1999 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Theatre / Drama, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Theatre / Drama, 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Theatre / Drama, 2004-2007 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Women's Studies (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Theatre & Dance, 2009 (Drawer F.3, Ovs folder 11)
- Five Year Plan
  - Humanities & Fine Arts - Five Year Plan, January 1969 (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
  - Social Sciences & Auxillary - Five Year Plan, January 1969 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Self-Study Reports
  - Communications Arts Department, February 1965 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Department of English, Joseph M. Doggett (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Speech Department (Box 9, Folder 11)